SOMA DEB

EMPLOY

PROFILE

Sales Professional with diverse experience of 06 years in Direct Sales, Consultative Sales, sales support, marketing and solution selling. Established strong working relationship with customers. Proficient management of sales operations. Possess strong communication and inter personal skills. **Attended** Masterclass on Product Management from INSEAD from LinkedIn.

CONTACT

Phone: 09613103032

Email: soma9deb@gmail.com Location: Guwahati, Assam

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Consultative Selling
- o B2B & B2C Sales Support
- o International Sales (US)
- Customer Relationship Management
- Cold Calling
- o Account Acquisition
- o Database Management
- o Order Management
- o Project Coordination
- CRM (Salesforce, Leadsquared)
- o Client Retention
- o Invoice Generation

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

- o Communication Skills
- Leadership Qualities
- o Team Player
- o Time Management
- o Quick Learner

EDUCATION

B.Sc. (Zoology) from Pandu College, Guwahati in 2016.

Scored 7.7 GPA

EMPLOYMENT DETAILS

Koenig Solutions | Assistant Manager - Inside Sales, Delhi (November 2022 - February 2023)

- Handled accounts for B2Bbusinesses and acquired new business on a weekly target basis.
- Understood clients need and pitched product according their need.
- Regular use of CRM to maintain records.
- Conducted meetings with Individual and Business entities and successfully concluded into deals.
- Followed up with customers after completion of sales to assess satisfaction and resolve technical or service concerns.
- Acquired business from domestic and international market.

Wiley NXT | Inside Sales Specialist, Bengaluru (Jan 2022 - Nov 2022)

- Accountable for generating business; exceeded targeted sales goals through continuous pursuit of new sales opportunities and expert closing of customer deals.
 - Played a key role in generating revenue worth INR 30 Lakhs
 - Acquired new as well as referral accounts
- Emphasized product features based on analysis of customers' needs.
- Maintained logs and records in the system.
- Determined needs, delivered solutions and overcame objections through consultative selling skills.
- Followed up with customers after completed sales to assess satisfaction and resolve technical or service concerns.
- Handled domestic and international market.
- Led a team of 9 members and supported them in handling the customer queries.
- Took sessions for the new members joining the team.

BYJU's - The Learning APP | Student Success Specialist, Bengaluru (Jun 2021 - Nov 2021)

- Facilitated academic and cognitive assessments to provide resourcereferrals according to individualized needs.
- Successfully handled student inquiries and resolved problems related to curriculum and course prerequisites.
- Directed students in clear definition of problem statement, precise research questions, proposed methodology and literature review.
- Maintained student database and electronic records for each student contact.
- Assisted students in selecting courses to align with interests and abilities

Mirania Data System | Data Entry Specialist, Guwahati (Aug 2019 – Jun 2021)

- Handled the responsibilities pertaining to Market Research, Data Entry and Social Media Management.
 - o Compiled data and reviewed information for accuracy prior to input.
 - Ensured timely updating of the database.
 - Evaluated source documents to locate needed information.
 - Located and corrected data entry errors and reported to management.
 - Searched, extracted and interpreted information to determine correct input procedure.

Lynchpin India | Marketing Officer, Guwahati (Sep 2016 – Jul 2019)

- 3years of B2B market experience. Revenue generation worth 30lakh/year.
- Worked for full sales cycle Lead generation to closure of lead
- Supported sales team with administrative assistance such as coordinating paperwork and responding to basic inquiries.
- Identified the customer requirements based on the market research.
- Measured and reported on results of marketing initiatives.
- Wrote copy for social media posts, promotional emails and other marketing collateral.
- Key role in retaining the existing accounts and successfully acquired new clients.
- Organized various events and exhibitions.